Badr HAMRAOUY

(709)701-2711 | hamraouy@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/badr-hamraouy/

Somerset, Toronto, ON K1P 4X0 (willing to relocate)

Eligible to work in Canada

Salesforce Developer & Administrator

Professional Summary

Hardworking Tech-savvy with **1 year** of experience as a **Java Swing Designer & Developer**, **3 years** of experience as an **IT Support Technician in both India and Hungary**, and with almost **2 years** of experience as an **IT Teacher**. Certified **Salesforce platform** <u>developer1</u> **& Administrator**.

Skills

- Apex, Visualforce, Lightning
- Java, Python, C++
- AWS, Azure, Google Cloud
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- SOQL, SOSL, SQL
- Salesforce APIs and integrations

- Agile software development (Scrum)
- Git, Visual Studio Code
- Object Oriented Programming
- Unified Modeling Language (UML)
- Problem-solving
- MySQL, MongoDB, SQL Server

Professional Experience

IT Teacher

Sep 2021 - Feb 2023

Regional Academy of Education and Training

Mohammedia, Morocco

- Introduced Algorithms and Programming Languages to learners based on their levels
- Networking and Operating Systems
- Managed, supervised and evaluated Classrooms (minimum 30 people per class)
- Planned lessons and developed courses

Service Desk Analyst

May 2019 - April 2021

Budapest, Hungary

Tata Consultancy Services

- Assisted users over the telephone, through e-mail/voice mail, and over web interface
- Diagnosed and solved software and hardware problems by giving step-by-step instructions
- Provided advanced support to Customer's PC using remote control tool
- Escalated unsolved calls to the appropriate IT team, Network/Server Support, Application Support team, or other Support teams
- Logged all calls in the Helpdesk tracking database/Service Management tool
- Instructed users on usage of application system
- Learned and implemented new technologies, tools processes, and policies
- Provided training to other staff members as required
- Documented new technical solutions in the knowledge base
- Documented and shared best practices with other colleagues

Badr Hamraouy Page 1 of 2

Technical Support Specialist

Tata Consultancy Services

Oct 2017 - Oct 2018 Kolkata, India

- Analysed and resolved of production issue (tickets) for applications used by customers and clients within SLA
- Daily status meeting with Support teams and business (French)
- Validated tickets logged in ITSM tool
- Acted as a French interpreter for the team to facilitate issue resolution
- Reported to project manager based on key performance indicators
- Tracked on a regular frequency, individual KPIs like average response time, etc.

Java Swing Designer & Developer (Internship)

Jan 2017 - Jun 2017

Upline Group

Casablanca, Morocco

- Designed and developed the GUI screens for the application using Java Swing
- Used Framework API with customized swing components to maintain the uniform look and feel
- Extensive use of swing components like JTable, JComboBox, JList, JCheckBox, etc
- Developed screen flows and new window layouts.
- Assisted in prototyping efforts and product design.

Java Swing Designer & Developer (Internship)

Jan 2016 - Jun 2016

Group ALLALI

Mohammedia, Morocco

- Developed new software systems and components.
- Identified and resolved issues proactively.
- Developed client slide components utilizing Java Swing framework.
- Maintained development methodology coding and design standards.

Education

Master of Science: IT methods applied in business management

Jul 2017

International University of Rabat

Rabat, Morocco

Recognized by World Education Services Canada as a Master's degree

Bachelor of Science: IT and Electronics

Jun 2014

Faculty of Sciences and Techniques

Mohammedia, Morocco

Recognized by World Education Services Canada as a Bachelor's degree (four years)

Certifications

Salesforce Platform Developer 1 [CRT-450]

Salesforce Certified Administrator

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

ORACLE CLOUD INFRUSTRUCTURE (OCI) Foundations 2021 Associate [1Z0-1085-21]

Languages: English: Fluent, French: Fluent, Arabic: Native

Badr Hamraouy Page 2 of 2